<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (Opinion)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 22:05:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Senseless Policy</title>
      <link>/blog/senseless-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 22:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/senseless-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is full of laws, policies, and rules that fall apart at the slightest iterrogation. Today I was met with one of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself at Best Buy returning a recently purchased power strip because it didn&amp;rsquo;t fulfil my needs. Specifically it had 12 plugs, but the layout was such that in reality only one pair of 6, or the other 6, could be used at any particular time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After handling the return, which involved no questions beyond &amp;ldquo;Did you open it?&amp;rdquo;, and resulted in a full refund to my credit card, I decided to go see if I could find an alternate model that would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a new strip that, based on the box art, seemed like it had more margin between plugs such that I could actually use them simultaneously. But having been recently burned I found a store employee, and asked if he&amp;rsquo;d mind opening the box so I could check out the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The employee in question, undoubtly &lt;em&gt;just following policy&lt;/em&gt; checked the box, and confirmed that we could have a look but only because there was no tape in our way. Had there been, we would have been unable to open the box together because that would turn the product into &amp;ldquo;open box&amp;rdquo; inventory (Which gets sold for slightly less).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the surface that &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; sound like a reaonable policy, but after just a moment of thought it should be obvious that, had the employee not allowed me to inspect the product, I could simply: Buy it, open the box after completing the transaction, decide I didn&amp;rsquo;t want it, and get an immediate refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only would that leave the store with the same piece of opened inventory, but they&amp;rsquo;d also be out the credit card processing fees involved in charging and refunding me. Not to mention giving me a worse customer service interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a great little example of why it&amp;rsquo;s so important that we think about the whole when we engage with designing and building systems, and consider the outcomes in aggregate. Someone probably thought it was a reasonable policy to say &amp;ldquo;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t open products&amp;rdquo;, but in totality it flies in the face of &amp;ldquo;We should make money by selling products to customers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence Day</title>
      <link>/blog/independence-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:36:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/independence-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://werd.io/2024/the-america-that-i-love&#34;&gt;Ben Werdmuller writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an America I’m delighted to be a part of; one that I’ve come to truly love. It’s the America that understands the impact it’s had and has, both on its own communities and on the world, and genuinely wants to do much better. &amp;hellip; It’s not the only America, and it’s not the loudest America. But it’s the best one, by far. I think it’s worth saying that I do love it; I want to support it; I want it to be the defining experience of being in and from this country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ben, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about America today, and my relationship with this nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not born on America&amp;rsquo;s shores, nor with any particular attachment to this land. Yet due to the happy little accidents called life, I find myself siting here now, celebrating this Independence Day as a bona fide American Citizen for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless things wrong with our nation, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t possible itemize them here for fear of implying that those faults I left out were on purpose, and mean less to me. It&amp;rsquo;s truly overwhelming just how much work we have ahead of us to live up to the ideals of Liberty, Justice, Freedom, and Independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind drifts to the following lines from the musical &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hamilton_(musical)&#34;&gt;Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron Burr: The constitution&amp;rsquo;s a mess.&lt;br&gt;
Alexander Hamilton: So it needs amendments.&lt;br&gt;
Aaron Burr: It&amp;rsquo;s full of contradictions.&lt;br&gt;
Alexander Hamilton: So is independence. We have to start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all of its numerous faults, I truly believe that today&amp;rsquo;s America is that &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s far from perfect, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got a start. We &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make this the America that lives up to our lofty ideals, but we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to fight for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not Worried for My Career</title>
      <link>/blog/im-not-worried-for-my-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 10:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/im-not-worried-for-my-career/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent conversation, someone asked me why people should bother learning to code anymore, when GenAI&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; / LLMs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; can just generate code for you these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the output of that conversation, this is a list of reasons why I am not worried for my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;its-not-about-writing-code&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#its-not-about-writing-code&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    It&amp;rsquo;s Not About Writing Code
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might sound conterintuitive to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in this field, but being a software developer is largely not about &lt;em&gt;developing&lt;/em&gt; software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other engineering diciplines, there seems to be a number of well understood and clearly distinct roles. Construction demands the input of architects, engineers, contractors, suveyors, crane operators, and a myriad of other participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is not as clear cut. I have not yet in my years on the job come across an individual whose job is strictly to write code based on plans laid by other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find ourselves taking on many different roles, from sitting down with the client and trying to build an understanding of what they want the software to do, to building prototypes, to putting on the architecture hat and thinking through not just &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to build, but &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to build it so that it meets the needs set forth by our client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even &lt;strong&gt;if&lt;/strong&gt; we conceeded that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to type out the code anymore, the rest of the activities leave us with plenty to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;someone-needs-to-check-the-work&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#someone-needs-to-check-the-work&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Someone Needs To Check the Work
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you decide to utilize a LLM to generate some code on your behalf, rather than typing it by hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How confident are you that the code generated is correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an experienced software engineer, you could look at the output, and if it&amp;rsquo;s fairly simple, you could confirm its correctness at a glance. If it&amp;rsquo;s more complicated, you have tools in your toolbox for that scenario too: You could write &lt;a href=&#34;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/UnitTest.html&#34;&gt;Unit Tests&lt;/a&gt; to confirm correctness for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In either case, your ability to confirm of the code does what you think it should, depends on yourself already having a mental model of how software works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you disagree: Why does anyone need to check the work? The software working is self-evident! If I click run, and it runs, then it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that I would say: You underestimate the subtle and disasterous ways in which systems can fail, that aren&amp;rsquo;t obvious. What would happen, if someone had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/null-license-plate-landed-one-hacker-ticket-hell/&#34;&gt;NULL as their license plate&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace &amp;ldquo;LLM&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Stack Overflow&amp;rdquo;, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that this isn&amp;rsquo;t a new problem in our industry. There have always been those who tried to get away with not really knowing what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whos-code-is-it&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#whos-code-is-it&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Who&amp;rsquo;s Code Is It?
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not a lawyer, so forgive me for any inacuracies here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, in the U.S., when someone pays you to write something for them, the something you&amp;rsquo;ve written is now their property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems simple enough. A client hires me to write an application for them, I do, I get paid, they have an app. Whatever they do from there is up to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can hire me to come make modifications in the future, they can hire someone else, they can toss it asside and decide to do something else entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if the code I &lt;em&gt;wrote&lt;/em&gt; for them was never &lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt; in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal battles are unfolding to answer questions exactly like this, &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubcopilotlitigation.com/&#34;&gt;developers are suing GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/legal/transactional/ny-times-sues-openai-microsoft-infringing-copyrighted-work-2023-12-27/&#34;&gt;newspapers are suing OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly the answers to these legal questions will be, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But if I was hiring people to do work for me, I&amp;rsquo;d err on the side of wanting to be confident the work actually belongs to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-computer-knows-how---not-why&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-computer-knows-how---not-why&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    The Computer Knows How - Not Why
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing another analogy to the physical world: there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_bridge_types&#34;&gt;many ways to build a bridge&lt;/a&gt;. Each bridge type undoubtedly has a laundry list of pros and cons, costs, time to build, difficulty to service, ability to withstand natural disassters, and more. I&amp;rsquo;m not a civil engineer, and I have no idea how these different bridge types stack up against each other. But I mention all of this, because the same characteristics are true about software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to build working software, from monoliths to microservices, dynamic vs. statically linked dependencies, object oriented vs. functional. As with bridges, there are many choices to make along the way when designing software, and there is no one &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt; answer. It takes understanding the context in which you are building, to make the best possible choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we trying to get someone out the door as fast as possible, to demo to potential investors, so that we can get money to build the &lt;em&gt;real thing&lt;/em&gt; later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we building in a life-or-death scenario, where the guaranteed correctness of our software outweighs financial concerns?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we anticipate that our code will be in use for months, years, or decades? The longer it is, the more likely we will need to deal with transitioning to new hardware, new maintanence staff, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These and more, are the kinds of considerations that set you up to design software fit for its purpose. As it stands, there&amp;rsquo;s no indication LLMs will be capable of taking on this mental labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative Artificial Intelligence.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embarrassment Is a Sign of Growth</title>
      <link>/blog/embarrassment-is-a-sign-of-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/embarrassment-is-a-sign-of-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the past couple of days, I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated this blog from Squarespace to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. In so doing, I had to review each of the existing posts, as part of the conversion process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found was, frankly, embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aware of my lacking writing abilities&lt;/a&gt;, but nothing makes that quite as clear as re-reading something you wrote a while back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I sat with my embarrassment, I considered deleting some of those old posts and giving myself a clean slate. Ultimately though, I decided to accept my shame as a sign of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, my past writing is worse than I&amp;rsquo;d like it to be. Hopefully my future writing will be better, but I accept that being bad at something is the first step on the journey to getting good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Isn&#39;t Mandatory</title>
      <link>/blog/speaking-isnt-mandatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 10:42:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/speaking-isnt-mandatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet era is marked by many things, but the sheer speed and volume of communication stands out to me as perhaps the most significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s always a new story breaking somewhere. When everything from wars to simple disagreements in our communities are played out on a public stage for all the world to see, there’s no moment devoid of topics we are each expected to take a stance on. Who rightfully deserves to win the war? Are you in favor of oppression or free speech? Surely you don’t support &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; people? Not speaking out may not seem like an option, after all if you don’t condemn bad things, you must implicitly support them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fear of being seen as someone who doesn’t care, or worse even outright supports bad things, can drive us to quickly adopt a posture. The problem is that we miss so much of the nuance of the world, in our rush to an opinion. The unfortunate truth is that we people have a tendency to have complicated motivations, which drive us to take actions with second and third order effects we never considered. It doesn’t help that our globally intertwined economy is too complex for any one person to really grasp the full picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A boon in our economy good, but if that money is spent on products that ultimately support nations that oppress their citizens, suddenly it’s bad again. Lowering emissions is great, but hardworking folks no longer being able to support their families is of course not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I advocating that we can never have any opinions? Absolutely not, public discourse is a cornerstone of any functional society. If we don’t discuss our thoughts, we will never grow beyond ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am saying is this: It’s okay not to speak when you’re not ready to. Sometimes you need to listen to others. Sometimes an issue is so far outside of your domain that you simply don’t have anything to say. And sometimes you need to reflect on a matter before you make up your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of those things are alright, speaking up every single time is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish Whatever You Want</title>
      <link>/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 17:15:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back at the start of the year, I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/a-reflection-on-2022/&#34;&gt;a brief reflection on the year that passed us in 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is so often the case, the beginning of the year came with lofty ideals about what the following year would contain&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Given that we’re now well over halfway&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; through the year, we’re at the point where it starts to become apparent that we won’t be living up to our ideals&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not living up to the expectations I have of myself is one of the most crippling fears in my life. It has at many occasions kept me from trying new things, given that I can’t be confident I will be any good at them. Among the activities curtailed by my fear, is the act of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a great writer, or indeed communicator in general&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I allow that to stop me from writing, because I’m scared it’ll read awkwardly, or the grammar will be wrong, or nobody will care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end however, you only get better by doing. And even if nobody cares now, maybe someone will in the future, even if that someone is just me. So ultimately this message is really for myself: Just publish it. It’s okay that it isn’t perfect. It’s even okay if you’re embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ex-manager, and mentor said these words to me more times than I could stand: “Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good”. I hate to say it, but he’s right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human obsession with starting over is really breathtaking, I’d love to understand it better someday.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;60.5%.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point: There used to be 250 more words here, all irrelevant to the overall point.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
