<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vision Pro on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/vision-pro/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (Vision Pro)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:34:35 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/vision-pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Vision Pro</title>
      <link>/blog/apple-vision-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 17:34:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/apple-vision-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I had an appointment at the Apple Store to demo the company’s newest product, the Apple Vision Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not up to speed, the Apple Vision Pro is an AR&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; headset that you wear, it has cameras and other sensors on the front, and small screens and lenses on the inside that you look at. The result is a convincing facsimile of the whole device being “see through”, with the notable exception that the software then allows you to interact with applications, which to you appear like they’re floating in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has a few videos on their site you can view to get a sense for what the device can do at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/guided-tour/&#34;&gt;https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/guided-tour/&lt;/a&gt;, that being said video truly does not do the experience justice. I would highly recommend anyone who’s the least bit curious to give this a go, worst case scenario you spend 30 minutes doing something different with your day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me the experience felt truly magical, in ways that technology hasn’t done for me in a while. The illusion was totally able to trick my brain into feeling like the apps were just floating there in space. The eye tracking (which is used like a cursor on a computer) is really good. It felt effortless to look at the button I wanted to tap. I walked away from the whole thing breath taken, and &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; tempted to buy one on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for my marriage sense prevailed, because the $3,500 price tag for the base model isn’t the kind of thing you buy and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; tell your wife about (at least not in my family), but I can absolutely see the appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/apple-vision-pro/IMG_1163.jpeg&#34;
    alt=&#34;A photo of me wearing the Apple Vision Pro, staring off into the distance.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;My first Vision Pro experience.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/apple-vision-pro/IMG_1162.jpeg&#34;
    alt=&#34;Second photo of myself wearing the Vision Pro, this time looking more directly towards the camera.&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I wore my &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypercritical.co&#34;&gt;Hypercritical&lt;/a&gt; shirt for the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who wears glasses, I was nervous about what that situation would look like at the store. I had taken a questionnaire at the time of booking, but it didn’t ask any specifics about my prescription, so I wasn’t sure what to expect on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that when you come in, they take your glasses and scan them on a machine. A little while later an employee comes out with the headset, already fitted with the correct lenses for you. But… how do they make sure they have your lenses? After all prescriptions come in many kinds. I was told that for this purpose, the individual Apple Store has over 860 different pairs of lenses sitting in the back room, to fit almost anyone right then and there in time for the demo. Mind blown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Augmented Reality.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
