<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (Life)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:46:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy</title>
      <link>/blog/legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:46:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/legacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve been worrying about my legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child learning the history of so many who came before me, I always wondered what there would be to say about me when it was all said and done.
Would I one day be a great physist?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Would I be immortalised on the periodic table by uncovering a new element?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I haphasardly fell into computing instead, I had dreams of being compared to Linus Torvalds and Richard Stallman&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; one day.
Of creating software so remarkably useful that it would solidify my name in computing history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the harsh truth is that for every person history remembers, millions are quietly forgotten. The odds are not on my side, in the grand scheme of what &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; have been doing on this globe for the past hundred-thousand years, it&amp;rsquo;s not likely that anything I do will matter &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse still, as the people that shaped my life begin to dissapear&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, it becomes increasingly clear to me that it&amp;rsquo;s damn near impossible for any of us to truly &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; one another in life. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to learn many things about their lives, the lives &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was a part of, that I simply didn&amp;rsquo;t see in the haze of living life through my own lense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, what chance do we have of knowing someone after they&amp;rsquo;re dead? What chance do we have of being remembered for who we were?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a walk with me through these lives&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m your friend, your lover, and your traitor&lt;br&gt;
Take a walk with me through my mind&lt;br&gt;
But I&amp;rsquo;m an unreliable narrator&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m your unreliable narrator&lt;br&gt;
- &amp;ldquo;Intros &amp;amp; Narrators&amp;rdquo; by Bastille&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is we don&amp;rsquo;t even really know ourselves. Everything I remember I do through the rose-tintented glasses of nostalgia, the innocence of youth, and the stories I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I no longer know the young guy who started a job at Google in 2016, and felt like he was the absolute shit for making it to the big leagues so early in his career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teenager who fell in love with his first girlfriend, and was so unprepared for the emotional rollercoaster of love and rejection, is now someone I can smile at as I recall how he felt. But it took years from being the person that had those experiences, to becoming a person that could look at them as an outside observer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about the 10 year old kid who had his whole world uprooted, when his mother got a job in the city and so they moved from the country to the suburbs? As I recall, he was absolutely shattered about losing the life he knew. He loved his small town, but would he still have loved it a decade later if it had become a barrier to his career prospects in the future? We will never know, because that me never got to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might all feel like a rather lengthy digression, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s something important here: Maybe the idea of legacy doesn&amp;rsquo;t even make sense, if there&amp;rsquo;s no constant self. After all, in the thought &amp;ldquo;I want to be remembered&amp;rdquo;, the &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; is rather central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legacy, what is a legacy?&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s planting seeds in a garden you never get to see.&lt;br&gt;
I wrote some notes at the beginning of a song someone will sing for me.&lt;br&gt;
America, you great unfinished symphony, you sent for me.&lt;br&gt;
- &amp;ldquo;Hamilton&amp;rdquo; by Lin-Manuel Miranda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dear son, you are my seed. Proverbially and literally, I planted you in this garden we call earth. And as I keep thinking about my legacy, these days my mind turns straight to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope for no greather honor than to see my son grow into a man of his own, and perhaps care &lt;em&gt;a little&lt;/em&gt; about who his old man was. I hope some of these ramblings I leave behind will be helpful in painting the picture of who I was, when eventually this is all that will be left of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physics were my first passion in school, and for a while it seemed I may pursue it for a living.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know he was a dick then, alright?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first lost my grandmother Urszula Mikulska in 2015. My grandfather Ove Hansen passed in the spring of 2022. My aunt Dorota Mikulska in the fall of 2024. I met two of my great-grandmothers, but they both died at an early enough time in my life that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt; to me in the same way.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
