<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tag on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/tag/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (Tag)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:53:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/tag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Google</title>
      <link>/blog/the-people-of-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:53:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-people-of-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently woke up from a stress dream involving my time at Google&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and as I came to, I only felt increasingly stressed at the realization that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to forget many of the events and faces that so greatly influenced those years of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed my time at Google from 2016 to 2018 was in many ways the foundation of my life as an adult, so although forgetting is only a natural part of the human condition, I want to take this opportunity to remember, and thank, those people who left their mark on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;angelique&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#angelique&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Angelique
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angelique belongs at the top of this list, not because of the alphabet&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but because she was the first link between me and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shannon&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#shannon&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Shannon
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shannon was a friend to all the people of &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/SGYns3cC4YY&#34;&gt;Techstop&lt;/a&gt;. I can&amp;rsquo;t recall a single time she didn&amp;rsquo;t bring positivity to a situation, despite many that didn&amp;rsquo;t truly warrant it.
She always brought a genuine (At least I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they were genuine) smile to the workplace, and that helped a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shannon is also one of few people who I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed in touch with since, though we don&amp;rsquo;t speak often, I cherish her friendship when we do. It&amp;rsquo;s ultimately what lead me to decide to write these things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fabiano&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#fabiano&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Fabiano
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabiano was my first manager at Google, and in fact my first &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; manager of any kind. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect of a manager back then, but Fabiano ticked all the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He way always honest, upfront, and supportive as a manager. When I messed up, I knew, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t chastised. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to appreciate just how difficult of a skill that is over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Fabiano at the helm, our team truly felt like a collaborative enterprise in bringing the very best to our fellow Googlers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fabio&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#fabio&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Fabio
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, we had both a Fabio and a Fabiano on the team, it lead to many a joke at their expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabio was a strong engineer, he lead the first internal project I got myself involved in, my first foray into the world of professional software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Fabio left our team to become a real honest &lt;a href=&#34;https://sre.google&#34;&gt;SRE&lt;/a&gt;, I remember once running into him at the elevator and uttering something like &amp;ldquo;Bro your code is shit!&amp;rdquo;.
I was frustrated with a bug I was working on, it was supposed to come across humorous, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it did. I regret that to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabio, thank you for the work you did for all Techstops worldwide. I will never forget what we built together. Sitting here now thinking about how proud I am to have been part of the project,
I&amp;rsquo;m honestly tearing up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tom&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tom&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Tom
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alex&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#alex&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Alex
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosmin&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cosmin&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Cosmin
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finbarr&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#finbarr&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Finbarr
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nataša&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#nata%c5%a1a&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Nataša
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will let you imagine why one might be stressed in the spring of 2025.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be confused with &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc.xyz&#34;&gt;Alphabet&lt;/a&gt; of course.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
