<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (Writing)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:25:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Embarrassment Is a Sign of Growth</title>
      <link>/blog/embarrassment-is-a-sign-of-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 07:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/embarrassment-is-a-sign-of-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the past couple of days, I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated this blog from Squarespace to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. In so doing, I had to review each of the existing posts, as part of the conversion process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found was, frankly, embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aware of my lacking writing abilities&lt;/a&gt;, but nothing makes that quite as clear as re-reading something you wrote a while back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I sat with my embarrassment, I considered deleting some of those old posts and giving myself a clean slate. Ultimately though, I decided to accept my shame as a sign of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, my past writing is worse than I&amp;rsquo;d like it to be. Hopefully my future writing will be better, but I accept that being bad at something is the first step on the journey to getting good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish Whatever You Want</title>
      <link>/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 17:15:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/publish-whatever-you-want/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back at the start of the year, I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://philip.mallegolhansen.com/blog/a-reflection-on-2022/&#34;&gt;a brief reflection on the year that passed us in 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is so often the case, the beginning of the year came with lofty ideals about what the following year would contain&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Given that we’re now well over halfway&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; through the year, we’re at the point where it starts to become apparent that we won’t be living up to our ideals&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not living up to the expectations I have of myself is one of the most crippling fears in my life. It has at many occasions kept me from trying new things, given that I can’t be confident I will be any good at them. Among the activities curtailed by my fear, is the act of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a great writer, or indeed communicator in general&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I allow that to stop me from writing, because I’m scared it’ll read awkwardly, or the grammar will be wrong, or nobody will care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end however, you only get better by doing. And even if nobody cares now, maybe someone will in the future, even if that someone is just me. So ultimately this message is really for myself: Just publish it. It’s okay that it isn’t perfect. It’s even okay if you’re embarrassed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ex-manager, and mentor said these words to me more times than I could stand: “Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good”. I hate to say it, but he’s right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human obsession with starting over is really breathtaking, I’d love to understand it better someday.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;60.5%.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point: There used to be 250 more words here, all irrelevant to the overall point.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
