<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>America on Philip Mallegol-Hansen</title>
    <link>/tags/america/</link>
    <description>Philip Mallegol-Hansen (America)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:36:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/tags/america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Independence Day</title>
      <link>/blog/independence-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 21:36:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/independence-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://werd.io/2024/the-america-that-i-love&#34;&gt;Ben Werdmuller writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s an America I’m delighted to be a part of; one that I’ve come to truly love. It’s the America that understands the impact it’s had and has, both on its own communities and on the world, and genuinely wants to do much better. &amp;hellip; It’s not the only America, and it’s not the loudest America. But it’s the best one, by far. I think it’s worth saying that I do love it; I want to support it; I want it to be the defining experience of being in and from this country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ben, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about America today, and my relationship with this nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not born on America&amp;rsquo;s shores, nor with any particular attachment to this land. Yet due to the happy little accidents called life, I find myself siting here now, celebrating this Independence Day as a bona fide American Citizen for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless things wrong with our nation, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t possible itemize them here for fear of implying that those faults I left out were on purpose, and mean less to me. It&amp;rsquo;s truly overwhelming just how much work we have ahead of us to live up to the ideals of Liberty, Justice, Freedom, and Independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind drifts to the following lines from the musical &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hamilton_(musical)&#34;&gt;Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaron Burr: The constitution&amp;rsquo;s a mess.&lt;br&gt;
Alexander Hamilton: So it needs amendments.&lt;br&gt;
Aaron Burr: It&amp;rsquo;s full of contradictions.&lt;br&gt;
Alexander Hamilton: So is independence. We have to start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all of its numerous faults, I truly believe that today&amp;rsquo;s America is that &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s far from perfect, but we&amp;rsquo;ve got a start. We &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; make this the America that lives up to our lofty ideals, but we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to fight for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
